<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economy on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/</link><description>Recent content in Economy on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demand</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/demand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/demand/</guid><description>Demand Functions Examples for demand functions : Marshallian demand function , Hicksian demand function . These functions use utility functions to determine demand packages.
In the first game iteration a conceptually easier method is used. This may not be the easiest to program or cheapest to compute.</description></item><item><title>Goods</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/goods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/goods/</guid><description>There are eight tradeable goods:
Food: At the start of the game, the biggest part of the population consists of subsistence farmers. They are able to produce surplus food to trade away to other communities (other farmers, aristocrats and workers). Farmers have to give a part of their food production as a contribution in kind to the aristocrats (serfdom). If farmers are supplied with machine parts, their food surplus rate increases.</description></item><item><title>Production</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/production/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/production/</guid><description>Production is separated in production by population and production in production buildings like factories and mines. Production by population is defined in Population .
The Leontief production function is used for output calculation. All production functions are defined in a “Production” class.
Agricultural Production:
Parameters: maxCerealsYield: amount of the maximum cereal production of a tile cerealsYieldRate: percentage per tile: 100% best place to grow cereals, 0% no cereals grow here f(farmers): triangle function with maximum value of 1.</description></item></channel></rss>