<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Nation on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/</link><description>Recent content in The Nation on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Armed Forces</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/armed-forces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/armed-forces/</guid><description>Armed Forces are organised in divisions and fleets.
Army: Divisions Divisions of the standing forces Divisions of the reserve forces Navy: Fleets During the game the proportions between standing and reserve forces changes. Also the proportions between overall army size and population changes. This depends on decisions made by the state. The decisions are influenced by the amount of funds available to pay for the standing army and for stockpiling weapons for the reserve army.</description></item><item><title>Industries</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/industries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/industries/</guid><description>Industries belong to a province (settlement) .
Industry Types Trade Port: Trade ports are ports used for international sea-going trade. They are a source of cotton and a sink for clothes, machine parts, and weapons. The state gets tariffs from imports and exports at the port. The prices at the port are set externally. For example the naval power of the state has an influence on prices.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Construction Cost</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/infrastructure-construction-cost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/infrastructure-construction-cost/</guid><description>Cost for constructing infrastructure is implemented as a network graph.
Nodes and Edges Nodes: tile locations Edges: connections between two adjacent tiles. The cost of the edge is the construction cost in money to connect two tiles. Use and Notes There are separate networks for land and sea tiles There are separate networks for each transport type: roads, railroads, sea lanes, waterways</description></item><item><title>National Stocks</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/national-stocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/national-stocks/</guid><description>The nation state is also an actor on the market place. The player can stockpile and use the resources wealth, food, tools, weapons and wine at the his capital city. As long as the game runs, the player has always a capital city. If his current capital gets conquered and/or destroyed, immediately another one of his cities gets promoted to capital city. If the capital was the last city, the player has lost the game.</description></item><item><title>Other Buildings</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/other-buildings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/other-buildings/</guid><description>Barracks: Sink for weapons. Stables, train stations, ports: See Transport Hub for details. &amp;lsquo;Cosmetic&amp;rsquo; buildings: Currently, there is no plan for implementation of farmland and pasture. They are only used to show map data. Farmland: Source of food. Not a building but represented on the map as a source of goods. Farmland does not have to be directly adjacent to a settlement. Pasture: Source of clothes, by farmers handcrafting clothes from the wool of the sheeps grazing on the pasture.</description></item><item><title>Population</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</guid><description>Populations are people living at a location and working in a broadly similar profession. For example a farming population is living in a settlement, working the fields surrounding their settlement. Or a population of workers living in a settlement, working in the two factories of their settlement. Populations either produce goods directly (farmers) or their labour is an input factor in mines and factories. All populations always consume food and consumer goods.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/research/</guid><description>There are techs which can be researched in every playthrough. There are breakthroughs which are not guaranteed to appear in every playthrough (see Surviving Mars). This helps to make every playthrough somewhat unique.</description></item><item><title>Settlements</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/settlements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/settlements/</guid><description>A settlement is defined by its population. The population is divided in different occupations:
Farmers: this is the default occupation. Aristocrats: consume food and clothes. Workers: work in factories and mines. Soldiers: man divisions located in barracks Details on settlements and populations are described in section 2.4 Population and Communities Depending on the available resources, individuals slowly shift between occupations. If there is not enough food at a settlement and there is farmable land available, the population shifts to farming.</description></item></channel></rss>