<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Nation on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/</link><description>Recent content in The Nation on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Population</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</guid><description>Populations are people living at a location and working in a broadly similar profession. For example a farming population is living in a settlement, working the fields surrounding their settlement. Or a population of workers living in a settlement, working in the two factories of their settlement. Populations either produce goods directly (farmers) or their labour is an input factor in mines and factories. All populations always consume food and consumer goods.</description></item><item><title>Settlements</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/settlements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/settlements/</guid><description>A settlement is defined by its population. The population is divided in different occupations:
Farmers: this is the default occupation. Aristocrats: consume food and clothes. Workers: work in factories and mines. Soldiers: man divisions located in barracks Details on settlements and populations are described in section 2.4 Population and Communities Depending on the available resources, individuals slowly shift between occupations. If there is not enough food at a settlement and there is farmable land available, the population shifts to farming.</description></item></channel></rss>