<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/</link><description>Recent content on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:29:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/introduction/</guid><description>Industrial Revolution is a real-time iteration of Civilization-like games. Civilization is a 4X game: eXplore, eXpand, eXploit and eXterminate. There is just one way to play: get as big as fast as possible and military reigns supreme (+90 % of unit types on the map are military units). Industrial Revolution does things differently:
The game is a real-time simulation of a society during the Industrial Revolution. It is a sandbox of interconnected systems.</description></item><item><title>Map</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map/</guid><description>The map represents a procedurally generated island nation. Its geographic and geologic features (landmass, height map, rivers) and other features like vegetation, settlements, roads, and other human constructions are procedurally created.
Map Data and Map View The data structure of the map is separated from the visual representation of the map. The map is a two-dimensional grid and is visually represented by rectangular (four-sided) tiles. Each grid location (or tile) has additional data fields which determines the tile characteristics:</description></item><item><title>Map Generation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map-generation/</guid><description>Detailed information about the map generation.
River Generation Rivers flow in straight lines from tile to tile. They do not flow diagonally to another tile. Generation: For every tile find the neighboring tile with the steepest decline between both tiles. This sets the flow direction of the tile. Set a base water amount to every tile using the respective moisture values. Go through all tiles according to their hight value starting at the highest tile.</description></item><item><title>Market</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/market/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/market/</guid><description>The markets are organised in the same way as the nation. On the national level, there is the National Market. On the provincial level, there are the Provincial Markets. One at each market town (settlement). Each population group and each industry (sources) acts as an individual trader. They are provincial traders.
The mechanism for trading is a kind of simulation of the behaviour at farmer’s markets. The mechanism is designed to provide a more ‘natural’ model of markets (some randomness, fixed ask prices, preference to trade locally).</description></item><item><title>Population</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</guid><description>Population content
Possible Features of Future Iterations The population acts as autonomous agents (farmers, artisans, aristocrats, miners, factory workers, soldiers, traders&amp;hellip;) These agents try to maximize their wealth (maybe try different objective functions&amp;hellip;)</description></item><item><title>Trade Manager</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trade-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trade-manager/</guid><description>Content for trade manager.</description></item><item><title>Trader</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trader/</guid><description>Each population group and each industry (sources) acts as an individual trader. They are provincial traders.</description></item><item><title>Story</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/story/</guid><description>Make the raising political tension and the outbreak of the Great War believable
By informing the player through messages about the political situation of the world By guiding the player with the military-industrial-complex mechanic into escalating political conflicts Background Story:
Industrial Revolution, Westernization, and Modernization of Japan History of South America, see Fortress of Humaita and Paraguayan War</description></item><item><title>Unsorted Content</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/unsorted-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/unsorted-content/</guid><description>Some Inspiration “In At The Gates you might find a shrouded mineral but when you reveal it, you might just get an iron deposit that lets you build some weapons or tools, but it could be a huge gold deposit that completely changes your game. They’re rare, but they exist. It’s not always going to a basic mineral – there’s a bigger spread of things that can happen.</description></item></channel></rss>