<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/</link><description>Recent content on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:29:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cargo</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/cargo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/cargo/</guid><description>As a part of the Transport System , Cargo is tranported from Transport Hubs to Transport Hubs by Transporters .
It has the fields:
TransportHub recipient path to the recipient (trade path, transport path, location path) goods type amount</description></item><item><title>Demand</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/demand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/demand/</guid><description>Demand Functions Examples for demand functions : Marshallian demand function , Hicksian demand function . These functions use utility functions to determine demand packages.
In the first game iteration a conceptually easier method is used. This may not be the easiest to program or cheapest to compute.</description></item><item><title>Goods</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/goods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/goods/</guid><description>There are eight tradeable goods:
Food: At the start of the game, the biggest part of the population consists of subsistence farmers. They are able to produce surplus food to trade away to other communities (other farmers, aristocrats and workers). Farmers have to give a part of their food production as a contribution in kind to the aristocrats (serfdom). If farmers are supplied with machine parts, their food surplus rate increases.</description></item><item><title>Industries</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/industries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/industries/</guid><description>Industries belong to a province (settlement).
Industry Types Trade Port: Trade ports are ports used for international sea-going trade. They are a source of cotton and a sink for clothes, machine parts, and weapons. The state gets tariffs from imports and exports at the port. The prices at the port are set externally. For example the naval power of the state has an influence on prices.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/introduction/</guid><description>Industrial Revolution is a real-time iteration of Civilization-like games. Civilization is a 4X game: eXplore, eXpand, eXploit and eXterminate. There is just one way to play: get as big as fast as possible and military reigns supreme (+90 % of unit types on the map are military units). Industrial Revolution does things differently:
The game is a real-time simulation of a society during the Industrial Revolution. It is a sandbox of interconnected systems.</description></item><item><title>Map</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map/</guid><description>The map represents a procedurally generated island nation. Its geographic and geologic features (landmass, height map, rivers) and other features like vegetation, settlements, roads, and other human constructions are procedurally created.
Map Data and Map View The data structure of the map is separated from the visual representation of the map. The map is a two-dimensional grid and is visually represented by rectangular (four-sided) tiles. Each grid location (or tile) has additional data fields which determines the tile characteristics:</description></item><item><title>Map</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/networks/</guid><description>Key features of the game world are mainly by using graphs. Four kind of network types are represented by graphs :
The network of bodies of water - ocean, rivers, estuaries The trade network : a network of markets The transport networks : a network of transport nodes and connections from tile to tile The construction cost graphs: the costs to build infrastructure from tile to tile</description></item><item><title>Map Generation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map-generation/</guid><description>Detailed information about the map generation.
River Generation Rivers flow in straight lines from tile to tile. They do not flow diagonally to another tile. Generation: For every tile find the neighboring tile with the steepest decline between both tiles. This sets the flow direction of the tile. Set a base water amount to every tile using the respective moisture values. Go through all tiles according to their hight value starting at the highest tile.</description></item><item><title>Market</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/market/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/market/</guid><description>The markets are organised in the same way as the nation. On the national level, there is the National Market. On the provincial level, there are the Provincial Markets. One at each market town (settlement). Each population group and each industry (sources) acts as an individual trader. They are provincial traders.
The mechanism for trading is a kind of simulation of the behaviour at farmer’s markets. The mechanism is designed to provide a more ‘natural’ model of markets (some randomness, fixed ask prices, preference to trade locally).</description></item><item><title>MarketComponent</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/classes/characterizing-classes/MarketComponent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/classes/characterizing-classes/MarketComponent/</guid><description>The MarketComponent class.</description></item><item><title>National Stocks</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/national-stocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/national-stocks/</guid><description>The nation state is also an actor on the market place. The player can stockpile and use the resources wealth, food, tools, weapons and wine at the his capital city. As long as the game runs, the player has always a capital city. If his current capital gets conquered and/or destroyed, immediately another one of his cities gets promoted to capital city. If the capital was the last city, the player has lost the game.</description></item><item><title>Other Buildings</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/other-buildings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/other-buildings/</guid><description>Barracks: Sink for weapons. Stables, train stations, ports: See Transport Hub for details. &amp;lsquo;Cosmetic&amp;rsquo; buildings: Currently, there is no plan for implementation of farmland and pasture. They are only used to show map data. Farmland: Source of food. Not a building but represented on the map as a source of goods. Farmland does not have to be directly adjacent to a settlement. Pasture: Source of clothes, by farmers handcrafting clothes from the wool of the sheeps grazing on the pasture.</description></item><item><title>Population</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/population/</guid><description>Populations are people living at a location and working in a broadly similar profession. For example a farming population is living in a settlement, working the fields surrounding their settlement. Or a population of workers living in a settlement, working in the two factories of their settlement. Populations either produce goods directly (farmers) or their labour is an input factor in mines and factories. All populations always consume food and consumer goods.</description></item><item><title>Production</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/production/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/economy/production/</guid><description>Production is separated in production by population and production in production buildings like factories and mines. Production by population is defined in Population .
The Leontief production function is used for output calculation. All production functions are defined in a “Production” class.
Agricultural Production:
Parameters: maxCerealsYield: amount of the maximum cereal production of a tile cerealsYieldRate: percentage per tile: 100% best place to grow cereals, 0% no cereals grow here f(farmers): triangle function with maximum value of 1.</description></item><item><title>Settlements</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/settlements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/the-nation/settlements/</guid><description>A settlement is defined by its population. The population is divided in different occupations:
Farmers: this is the default occupation. Aristocrats: consume food and clothes. Workers: work in factories and mines. Soldiers: man divisions located in barracks Details on settlements and populations are described in section 2.4 Population and Communities Depending on the available resources, individuals slowly shift between occupations. If there is not enough food at a settlement and there is farmable land available, the population shifts to farming.</description></item><item><title>Trade Manager</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trade-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trade-manager/</guid><description>Content for trade manager.</description></item><item><title>Trade Network</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trade-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trade-network/</guid><description>The trade network is a “minimum spanning tree” of all markets on the map. The Dijkstra-algorithm is used for pathfinding, since it is not possible to use an heuristic as in the A*-algorithm (is that true?).</description></item><item><title>Trader</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/trade-system/trader/</guid><description>Each population group and each industry (sources) acts as an individual trader. They are provincial traders.</description></item><item><title>Transport Hub</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-hub/</guid><description>The Transport Hub is part of the Transport System . There are three main types of transport hubs:
Stables: place where ox-wagons are stationed for road transport. Train stations: trains are available at train stations for rail transport. Ports: barges for river transport on water ways and schooners for coastal transport as well as clippers for ocean-going transport on sea lanes are anchored at ports. Features A Transport Hub is located on a tile.</description></item><item><title>Transport Network</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-network/</guid><description>The Transport Network is part of the Transport System .
At startup the game generates a Transport Network. This network includes roads, sea lanes, and waterways.
The trade network is a “minimum spanning tree” of all markets on the map.</description></item><item><title>Transporter</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transporter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transporter/</guid><description>The Transporter is part of the Transport System . It is located at its Transport Hub waiting for Cargo. After loading Cargo , the Transporter transports the Cargo to its target Transport Hub.
Components TransporterComponent - the characterizing class of the Transporter SelectableComponent MovingObject Behavior The Transporter moves from its Transport Hub to another Transport Hub. The Transporter &amp;ldquo;loads&amp;rdquo; the initial Cargo: void LoadCargo(List&amp;lt;Cargo&amp;gt;) If there is more Cargo at the Transport Hub that has the target Transport Hub also in its transport path, the Transporter &amp;ldquo;loads&amp;rdquo; it as well.</description></item><item><title>TransporterComponent</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/classes/characterizing-classes/TransporterComponent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/classes/characterizing-classes/TransporterComponent/</guid><description>The TransporterComponent class.
Fields Transporter Type (train, ox-wagon, barge, schooner, clipper) List of Cargos Transport Connection Type (road, rail, sea lane, waterway) Transport Path (path for the transport network)</description></item><item><title>TransportHubComponent</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/classes/characterizing-classes/TransportHubComponent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/classes/characterizing-classes/TransportHubComponent/</guid><description>The TransportHubComponent class.</description></item><item><title>Story</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/story/</guid><description>Make the raising political tension and the outbreak of the Great War believable:
By informing the player through messages about the political situation of the world By guiding the player with the military-industrial-complex mechanic into escalating political conflicts Background Story:
Industrial Revolution, Westernization, and Modernization of Japan History of South America, see Fortress of Humaita and Paraguayan War</description></item><item><title>Unsorted Content</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/unsorted-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/unsorted-content/</guid><description>Some Inspiration “In At The Gates you might find a shrouded mineral but when you reveal it, you might just get an iron deposit that lets you build some weapons or tools, but it could be a huge gold deposit that completely changes your game. They’re rare, but they exist. It’s not always going to a basic mineral – there’s a bigger spread of things that can happen.</description></item></channel></rss>