<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Interface on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/</link><description>Recent content in User Interface on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Menu Panel</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/game-menu-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/game-menu-panel/</guid><description>The Game Menu panel shows the basic game control functions like exiting the game. It is an UI element of the Map Scene. It is a modal UI element and by default it is not visible. The panel has the following functions:
Button to close the Game Menu panel (&amp;ldquo;back to game&amp;rdquo;) Button to save the game Button to go to the Main Menu scene Button to exit the game</description></item><item><title>Ledger Panel</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/ledger-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/ledger-panel/</guid><description>The Ledger panel shows information for about several game systems. It is an UI element of the Map Scene. It is a modal UI element and by default it is not visible.
The ledger contains the following pages:
List of Settlements . Providing an overview of all settlements with following information: Name of settlement Population count List of Markets . Name of market (in most cases name of settlement) Sub-list with prices of all resources at market Other components of the Ledger panel:</description></item><item><title>Main Panel</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/main-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/main-panel/</guid><description>The Main Panel is an UI element of the Map Scene. It is always visible. It has the following functions:
Label with current date Buttons for time control: Button to slow time Button to pause time Button to accelerate time Button to open the Ledger panel Button to open the Game Menu panel</description></item><item><title>National Stocks Panel</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/national-stocks-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/user-interface/national-stocks-panel/</guid><description>The National Stocks panel shows the resources currently stockpiled in the National Stocks . It is an UI element of the Map Scene. It is always visible.</description></item></channel></rss>