<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Game World on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/</link><description>Recent content in Game World on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Body of Water Network</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/body-of-water-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/body-of-water-network/</guid><description>All bodies of water (ocean, rivers, lakes, estuaries) are represented by a network graph.
Nodes and Edges Nodes: tile locations (using all three dimensions) Edges: no values are used Use and notes The z-dimension of the tile location is used depending on the type of body of water.</description></item><item><title>Map</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map/</guid><description>The map represents a procedurally generated island nation. Its geographic and geologic features (landmass, height map, rivers) and other features like vegetation, settlements, roads, and other human constructions are procedurally created.
Map Data and Map View The data structure of the map is separated from the visual representation of the map. The map is a two-dimensional grid and is visually represented by rectangular (four-sided) tiles. Each grid location (or tile) has additional data fields which determines the tile characteristics:</description></item><item><title>Map Generation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/map-generation/</guid><description>Detailed information about the map generation.
River Generation Rivers flow in straight lines from tile to tile. They do not flow diagonally to another tile. Generation: For every tile find the neighboring tile with the steepest decline between both tiles. This sets the flow direction of the tile. Set a base water amount to every tile using the respective moisture values. Go through all tiles according to their hight value starting at the highest tile.</description></item><item><title>Networks</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/game-world/networks/</guid><description>Key features of the game world are mainly by using graphs. Four kind of network types are represented by graphs :
The body of water network - ocean, rivers, estuaries The trade network : a network of markets The transport networks : a network of transport nodes and links from tile to tile The construction cost graphs : the costs to build infrastructure from tile to tile</description></item></channel></rss>