<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/introduction/</guid><description>Industrial Revolution is a real-time iteration of Civilization-like games. Civilization is a 4X game: eXplore, eXpand, eXploit and eXterminate. There is just one way to play: get as big as fast as possible and military reigns supreme (+90 % of unit types on the map are military units). Industrial Revolution does things differently:
The game is a real-time simulation of a society during the Industrial Revolution. It is a sandbox of interconnected systems.</description></item><item><title>Story</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/story/</guid><description>Make the raising political tension and the outbreak of the Great War believable:
By informing the player through messages about the political situation of the world By guiding the player with the military-industrial-complex mechanic into escalating political conflicts Background Story:
Industrial Revolution, Westernization, and Modernization of Japan History of South America, see Fortress of Humaita and Paraguayan War</description></item><item><title>Unsorted Content</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/unsorted-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/unsorted-content/</guid><description>Some Inspiration “In At The Gates you might find a shrouded mineral but when you reveal it, you might just get an iron deposit that lets you build some weapons or tools, but it could be a huge gold deposit that completely changes your game. They’re rare, but they exist. It’s not always going to a basic mineral – there’s a bigger spread of things that can happen.</description></item></channel></rss>