<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Transport System on Industrial Revolution Documentation</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/</link><description>Recent content in Transport System on Industrial Revolution Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cargo</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/cargo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/cargo/</guid><description>As a part of the Transport System , Cargo is tranported from Transport Hubs to Transport Hubs by Transporters .
It has the fields:
TradeComponent recipient Transport Hub targetTransportHub path to the recipient (trade path, transport path, location path) goods type amount</description></item><item><title>Transport Hub</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-hub/</guid><description>The Transport Hub is part of the Transport System . There are three main types of transport hubs:
Stables: place where ox-wagons are stationed for road transport. Train stations: trains are available at train stations for rail transport. Ports: barges for river transport on water ways and schooners for coastal transport as well as clippers for ocean-going transport on sea lanes are anchored at ports. Features A Transport Hub is located on a tile.</description></item><item><title>Transport Network</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transport-network/</guid><description>The Transport Network is part of the Transport System .
At startup the game generates a Transport Network. This network includes roads, sea lanes, and waterways.
Nodes and Edges Nodes: tile location and type of transport (e.g. road crossing, rail crossing, train station, port) Edges: links between to adjacent tiles. The nodes of the edge define its type. E.g. if both nodes are of type road crossing, the edge is a road.</description></item><item><title>Transporter</title><link>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transporter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nihamawassa.github.io/heartland/docs/transport-system/transporter/</guid><description>The Transporter is part of the Transport System . It is located at its Transport Hub waiting for Cargo. After loading Cargo , the Transporter transports the Cargo to its target Transport Hub.
Components TransporterComponent - the characterizing class of the Transporter SelectableComponent MovingObject Behavior The Transporter moves from its Transport Hub to another Transport Hub. The Transporter &amp;ldquo;loads&amp;rdquo; the initial Cargo: void LoadCargo(List&amp;lt;Cargo&amp;gt;) If there is more Cargo at the Transport Hub that has the target Transport Hub also in its transport path, the Transporter &amp;ldquo;loads&amp;rdquo; it as well.</description></item></channel></rss>